Guide to the George Gissing Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
George Gissing collection
1868-1957
GEN MSS 286
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.2
(10 boxes) + 1 portfolio
Contains letters from George Gissing to various people, including Eduard Bertz, Edward Clodd, Algernon Gissing, Ellen Gissing, Catherine Gissing, Margaret Bedford Gissing, Thomas Waller Gissing, and Walter L. Gissing; third party letters, including those between Gabrielle Fleury and Eduard Bertz; manuscripts and notes of writings by Gissing and others; agreements between Gissing and publishers; certificates that Gissing earned in school; a few photographs of Gissing; and material collected by Percival M. Stone about Gissing's time in Waltham, Mass.
Gissing, George, 1857-1903
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Source information is recorded on the folders. Many items in this collection were the gift of George Matthew Adams in memory of Harriet Breese Adams. Two cases with his mark have been retained as samples (Box 6, folder 105a, and Box 7, folder 148a). For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 9: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to George Gissing, acquired by the library from a variety of sources. Materials incorporated into the collection prior to January 1997 have been organized into three series, Correspondence, Writings, and Other. Materials added to the collection since that time are located in Series IV, Additions since January 1997, listed in the order in which they were added.
Brothers and sisters; Brothers; Fathers and sons; Mothers and sons; Bertz, Eduard, 1853-1931; Clodd, Edward, 1840-1930; Fleury, Gabrielle Marie Edith, 1868-1954; Gissing, Algernon, 1860-1937; Gissing, Catherine; Gissing, Ellen, 1867-; Gissing, George, 1857-1903; Gissing, Margaret Bedford; Gissing, Thomas Waller; Gissing, Walter L., 1892?-; Stone, Percival M.
- Correspondence, Series I
  - LETTERS FROM GEORGE GISSING
    - ALS to [the Authors Syndicate], Villa Lournet, Ciboure, St. Jean de Luz, France, 1902 Nov 13 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ALS to George Bainton, Agbrigg, 1890 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ALS to Martha McCulloch Barnes, Rome, 1897 Nov (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Scope and Contents
      Accompanied by a photograph inscribed to Miss Barnes and dated 1899 Feb.
    - 189 letters and postcards to Eduard Bertz, 1887-1903 (Box 1, Folder 4-16)
    - Autograph postcard to [Eduard Bertz], 1890 Feb 15 (Box 1, Folder 16a)
      Postcard addressed to E[llen] S. Gissing
    - 17 ALS to A. Bowes, Lindow Grove, Alderly Edge [Manchester], 1873 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      To his school friend.
    - ALS to [A.] Bowes, Lindow Grove, [18]73 Apr 23 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 6 ALS to [Edward] Clodd, 1895-1903 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - ALS to Edward Clodd, Paris, 1899 Nov 7 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      On literary and personal matters.
    - ALS to William Morris Colles, Brixton, S. W., 1893 Sep 19 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - ALS to William Morris Colles, Eversley, Worple Road, Epsom, 1895 Mar 6 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Removed from: The Odd Women by George Gissing (London, 1893).
    - ALS to William Morris Colles, Budleigh Salterton, [18]97 Feb 18 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - ALS to Stephen Crane, [Paris], 1899 Nov 20 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Removed from: Veranilda by George Gissing (London, 1904).
    - 21 ALS to Algernon Gissing, 1883-93 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Letters and postcards to Algernon Gissing, 1878-84 (Box 2, Folder 26-34)
    - Letters and postcards to Algernon Gissing, 1895-1903, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35-47)
    - 3 ALS to Catherine Gissing, 1886-88 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - 5 ALS to Catherine Gissing, 1886-90, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - 6 ALS to Catherine Gissing, [London], 1888-91 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - 4 ALS and 1 AL (incomplete?) to Ellen Gissing, 1885-89, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - 20 ALS to Ellen Gissing, 1886-89, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 52)
      On personal, family, and literary matters.
    - 5 ALS to Ellen Gissing, 1889-91 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      On family and literary matters.
    - 6 ALS to Ellen Gissing, 1889-1901 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      On family matters.
    - [Empty folder] (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - 1 ALS and 1 AL (signature cut out) to Margaret Gissing, 1885, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - ALS to Margaret Gissing, Cotrone, 1897 Nov 26 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - 2 ALS to Margaret Bedford Gissing, Lindow Grove, 1872, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - ALS to Margaret Bedford Gissing, Alderley, [1874] Apr 1 (Box 4, Folder 59)
      Appended are two of his early poems, "On a Dead Primrose, Plucked in Early Spring" and "The Sky at Sunset."
    - 9 ALS to [Margaret Bedford Gissing], 1889-1903, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - 5 ALS to Thomas Waller Gissing, [1868-69] (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - 63 ALS to Walter Gissing, 1896-1902, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 62-65)
    - ALS to Will[iam Gissing], 5 Hanover St., Islington, N., 1880 Mar 27 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - ALS to "My dear Grandfather," Victoria Place, [Wakefield, England], [1875] Sep 1 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - ALS to "My dear little Sister," Lindow Grove, 1871 Apr 3 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - 7 Christmas cards to members of his family, 1879-88, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - ALS to Harry [Hick], Eversley, Worple Road, Epsom, 1896 Jan 16 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      Removed from: By the Ionian Sea by George Gissing (London, 1901).
    - 8 ALS to Harry Hick, 1897-1902 (Box 4, Folder 71)
      On personal affairs, with frequent mention of literary matters.
    - ALS to Frederick George Kitton, St. Jean de Luz, 1903 Feb 8 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      Removed from: Forster's Life of Dickens by George Gissing (London, 1903).
    - ALS to [William R. Macdonell], Nievre, 1900 Sep 17 (Box 4, Folder 73)
      With a pencil note by A. G. Macdonell.
    - Signed receipt to James B. Pinker for £254.9.4, 1899 Sep 27 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - 3 ALS and 1 APCS to William G. Stannard, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - 3 ALS and 3 APCS to Herbert H. Sturmer, 1896-98 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - ALS to Mr. Sturmer, Roma, 1898 Feb 1 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      Removed from: Charles Dickens by George Gissing (London, 1898).
    - 3 ALS to Mr. Tinckam, 1894-97 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - ALS to William Wallace Whitelock, Paris, 1901 Jan 11 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - ALS without salutation, [1887] (Box 4, Folder 80)
      Concerning his refusal of Bentley's offer to publish Clement Dorricott as a book.
    - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Eversley, Worple Road, Epsom, 1895 Nov 10 (Box 4, Folder 81)
      Removed from: The Private Papers of Henry Ryecroft by George Gissing (Westminster, 1903).
    - ALS to [Authors' Syndicate?], 1901 Jun 20 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      Removed from: The Pickwick Papers by Charles Dickens (London, 1899).
  - LETTERS TO GEORGE GISSING
    - Bertz, Eduard. 3 AL (first drafts only), 15, Alexandrinenstrasse, Potsdam, [Germany], [1897]-1902 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - THIRD PARTY LETTERS
    Bertz, Eduard
    - AL (first draft only) to Gabrielle Gissing, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 84)
      Sometime prior to the death of her husband, George Gissing.
    - 5 ALS to [Heinrich Rehfeldt], Middlesex, England, 1880 (Box 5, Folder 85)
      With references to George Gissing. In German.
    - Gissing, Algernon. 3 ALS to Eduard Bertz, Castlerigg Cottage, Keswick, [Cumberland, England], 1904-05 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Gissing, Ellen S. 2 ALS to Eduard Bertz, Wakefield, [England], 1890, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Gissing, Gabrielle. 24 ALS and postcards to Eduard Bertz, 1899-1906, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 88)
      Concerning George Gissing. One letter and seven postcards are in English, the remainder in French.
    - Gissing, Roland. ALS to George Matthew Adams, Cochrane, Alberta, [Canada], 1951 Nov 4 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Gissing, Walter L. ALS to Eduard Bertz, Gresham's School, Holt, Norfolk, [England], [1904 Feb] (Box 5, Folder 90)
      This letter was enclosed in a letter from Ellen S. Gissing to Eduard Bertz dated 1904 Feb 12.
    - Moore, George. 2 TLS to J. R. Wells, London, 1928 Jul 17 (Box 5, Folder 91)
      Concerning the introduction he is to write for Workers in the Dawn. With envelope. Removed from: Workers in the Dawn by George Gissing (New York, 1930).
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries. Fragment of envelope to Algernon Gissing, Switzerland (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Roberts, Morley. ALS to Eduard Bertz, London, 1893 Feb 6 (Box 5, Folder 93)
      Contains references to George Gissing.
    - Sacher-Masoch, Aurora (Rumelin) von. 5 ALS to Eduard Bertz, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 94)
      In German. Concerning George Gissing
    - Shafer, Robert
      - 2 ALS to Mrs. Frank Capra, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 95)
        Concerning her copy of Workers in the Dawn, revised by Gissing. Removed from: Workers in the dawn by George Gissing (Garden City, 1935).
      - TLS to Ralph T. Howey, Cincinnati, 1934 Jul 21 (Box 5, Folder 96)
        Concerning the revised copy of Gissing's Workers in the Dawn. Removed from: Workers in the Dawn by George Gissing (Garden City, 1935).
    - Wells, Herbert George. ALS to Edmund Gosse, Pied de Port, France, 1903 Dec 26 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      Pertaining to the last illnesss of George Gissing. Note signed E.G. on p. 3: "George Gissing died the next day, December 27, 1903."
    - Unidentified. 3 manuscript notes, 1900, 1904, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 98)
      In German.
- Writings, Series II
  - WRITINGS OF GEORGE GISSING
    - "Angelica: A Poem in Eight Cantos", 1872-74 (Box 6, Folder 99)
      Canto I, two versions. Signed.
    - "Answer to Goldsmith's Criticism on Hamlet's Soliloquy", 1872 Jul 22 (Box 6, Folder 100)
      Autograph manuscript notes, signed with initials.
    - "Ariodante and Ginevra"
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Box 6, folder 113
    - "The Battle of Roncesvalles", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 101)
      Autograph manuscript of a poem, probably written when Gissing was between 14 and 16 years of age. The poem is dedicated to his mother, Mrs. T. W. Gissing.
    - "A Capitalist", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 102)
      Autograph manuscript, signed.
    - "Carlyle's Statue", 1883 Apr 27 (Box 6, Folder 103)
      Manuscript sonnet, signed G.R.G.
    - "The Coming of Autumn", 1874 Sep (Box 6, Folder 104)
      Autograph poem, signed.
    - "The Day of Silence"
      - Autograph manuscript, signed, with numerous changes in the author's hand, [1895?] (Box 6, Folder 105)
      - Box, with mark of George Matthew Adams, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 105a)
    - "A Description of and Critical Dissertation upon Fingal, a Poem of Ossian" (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Autograph manuscript, written in youth.
    - "A Despot on Tour", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 107)
      Autograph manuscript short story, signed.
    - "A Drug in the Market", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - "A Friend in Need" (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - "The Grandfather's New Year's Story", [1873?] (Box 6, Folder 110)
      Autograph manuscript, signed G.R.G. Addressed on verso of leaf 7 to "The editor of 'Chatterbox.'" Probably written when Gissing was 16 years of age, for the coming New Year is referred to as 1874.
    - "Harper! Strike thy Harp Again!", 1872 Jul 13 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - "Italia", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - "King Richard I"; "The Tragedy of Tancra and Clarinda"; "Ariodante and Ginevra", [Wakefield], 1869 (Box 6, Folder 113)
      3 manuscript dramas written in childhood, in a notebook with covers wanting. Laid in is a partial copy of "King Richard I", [Wakefield?], 1871.
    - "My First Rehearsal", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 114)
      Autograph manuscript, signed. Bound in black leather.
    - "Of Good Address", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - "On a Dead Primrose"
      See: Box 4, folder 59
    - "Our Shakesperian Studies," Manchester, [187-?] (Box 6, Folder 116)
      Heavily corrected galley proof of an article for the Owens College Magazine.
    - "Preface," [Manchester], [187-?] (Box 6, Folder 117)
      Corrected galley proof of an editorial from the Owens College Magazine.
    - "Ravenna"
      - Autograph manuscript, signed, [1873] (Box 6, Folder 118)
        Signed "G.R.G." Poem was awarded the prize for English poetry at Owens College.
      - Fair copy inscribed "A Bowes, with author's best wishes, GRG", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "The Sky at Sunset"
      See: Box 4, folder 49
    - "To A.F.G.", 1983 May 5 (Box 6, Folder 120)
      To Algernon Gissing. Manuscript sonnet, signed G. G.
    - "To My Friend Eduard Bertz with a Copy of Tennyson's Poems", 1879 Apr (Box 6, Folder 121)
      Manuscript poem, signed "GRG. April 1879."
    - "The Town Traveler," Epsom, [1897] (Box 6, Folder 122)
      Autograph manuscript, signed, in 27 chapters, about 80,000 words. With a number of corrections and additions in the author's hand.
    - "The Tragedy of Tancra and Clarinda"
    - "Under an Umbrella" (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - "Verses by G. R. Gissing, 1869 to [1882]", [1869-82] (Box 6, Folder 124)
      Autograph manuscript notebook. Each piece dated.
    - Vergil's Georgics, pages 458-74 of Book II (Box 6, Folder 125)
      Copied in Latin and translated into English by Gissing.
    - "Walks about Ilkley," Wakefield, 1872 Jul (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - "The Whirlpool," Paris, 1899 June 18 (Box 6, Folder 127)
      4 lines copied and sent "To Miss Ada Morse from George Gissing."
    - "Winter", [1875 Jan] (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Blackburne, phrenologist. "The Phrenological Sketch of Master [George] Gissing 13," Wakefield., 1870 Oct (Box 6, Folder 129)
      Autograph manuscript. Accompanied by a phrenological chart and register of George Gissing, 1870 Oct and a printed form filled in by Professor Blackburne.
    - Curtis, Anthony. "A Portrait of George Gissing", 1957 Nov (Box 6, Folder 130)
      Script (mimeographed copy) produced by Sasha Moorsom for the BBC. Inscribed by the author, 1959 Feb 20. Manuscript note at head of title: "BBC script not to be quoted or published in any form."
    - Mason, Walt. "Famous Too Late", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 131)
      Typewritten poem, signed, with manuscript corrections, about George Gissing. Released by the George Matthew Adams Service on Tuesday, 1936 Apr 14. Removed from: New Grub Street by George Gissing (London, Smith, Elder & Co., 1891).
    - Morley, Christopher Darlington. "A Note on George Gissing," The Bowling Green, [1927] (Box 6, Folder 132)
      Autograph manuscript, signed, with numerous corrections.
    - Rogers, Catherine. "Motivation in the Novels of George Gissing", 1916 (Box 6, Folder 133-134)
      Carbon typewritten copy of an M.A. thesis, Graduate Division, University of California.
- Other, Series III
  - AGREEMENTS WITH PUBLISHERS
    - Bentley, Richard & Son, London, 1889 Sep 30 (Box 7, Folder 135)
      For the purchase of the copyright to The emancipated. Signed by Gissing and Richard Bentley and Son. Witnessed by Morley Roberts and Nathaniel T. Beard, London. Form printed in red and black. Names and dates supplied in manuscript.
    - Blackie & Son, limited, Glasgow, 1897 Sep 6 (Box 7, Folder 136)
      - For publication of a biography of Charles Dickens in the "Victorian era series." Typewritten, signed by Walter W. Blackie, secretary, and Gissing. Witnessed by Thos. Lockhead, Jas. Lang, Algernon Gissing, and Catherine Gissing., 1897 Sep 6
    - Chapman and Hall, limited, London, 1884 Mar 13 (Box 7, Folder 137)
      To publish the Unclassed, signed by F. M. Chapman, managing director. Printed form. Names and dates supplied in manuscript.
    - Remington & Co., London
      - Three receipts to George R. Gissing, 1880 (Box 7, Folder 138)
        Acknowledging the payment of £125 for the publication of Workers in the Dawn.
      - Terms offered to George Gissing for the publication of his Workers in the Dawn, London, 1880 Feb 23 (Box 7, Folder 139)
        Printed form letter, with the terms of publications, names, and dates supplied in an unidentified hand. Removed from: Workers in the Dawn by George Gissing (London, 1880).
  - CERTIFICATES
    - Model drawing, from the Quaker boarding school at Alderley Edge, 1869 May 17 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - Freehand drawing and geometry, from the Quaker boarding school at Alderley Edge, 1870 May 10 (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - Examination in physical geometry (First Class award), 1872 Apr 29 (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - Examination in acoustics, light, and heat (Second Class award), 1872 May 1 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Examination in theoretical mechanics (Second Class award), 1872 May 11 (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - Passing the Oxford Local Examination as a junior candidate at Manchester (First Division), 1872 (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - Honor, from Owens College, Manchester, for the Higher Junior (A) Greek class, 1872-3
    - Honor, from Owens College, Manchester, for the Higher Junior (A) Latin class, 1872-3
    - Honor, from Owens College, Manchester, for the Junior German class, 1872-3
    - Studentship and good conduct from Owens College, Manchester, 1872-75 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - Matriculation, from the University of London, 1874 Jul 29
    - Honor, from the University of London, certifying that Gissing was first in the list of candidates who obtained honors in English, 1875 Oct 20
    - Examination for the degree of Bachelor of Arts, from the University of London, 1875 Oct 20
    - Honor, from the University of London, certifying that Gissing was first in the list of candidates who obtained honors in Latin, 1875 Oct 20
  - NOTES & DRAWINGS
    - "Account of books etc.", 1880-98 (Box 7, Folder 147)
      Autograph manuscript diagrams, showing the receipts from individual publications during each year.
    - Caricatures and a sketch by Gissing, 1871 (Box 7, Folder 148)
      In ink and in pencil. Two of the caricatures are accompanied by verses with the titles, "W---m G---g's life indoors and out" and are signed "G.R.G", [Lindow Grove, Alderley Edge, Cheshire?]. Gissing's two brothers, William and Algernon, are the subjects of two of the caricatures; Gissing is himself the subject of the third. The sketch is a copy from Doré's Don Quixote.
    - Portfolio for caricatures and a sketch by Gissing, with mark of George Matthew Adams (Box 7, Folder 148a)
    - Commonplace book, 1889-95 (Box 7, Folder 149)
      Manuscript quotations entered by the Gissing family and friends. Many leaves blank. One pen and ink sketch, one water color drawing. Bound in cardboard with chromolithograph on cover.
    - Drawing. Notes on, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 150)
      Autograph manuscript notes. Also on on Albrecht Dürer's engraving, followed by six pencil sketches. Colored bookplate, unattached of Harry Bache Smith.
    - French phonetics. Manuscript notes on, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 151)
      Removed from: Love's Labour's Lost by William Shakespeare (London, [1864]).
    - Notebook containing autograph manuscript notes about his novels, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 152)
      Publisher, date, numbers of copies sold, and royalties, from The Unclassed (1884) to The Private Papers of Henry Ryecrofs (1902). Black paper covers, with calendars for 1889 and 1899 inside front cover.
    - "Notes. G. R. G.", 1877 (Box 7, Folder 153)
      Autograph manuscript, in a brown leather-covered notebook, containing some quotations and suggestions for plots. A brief itinerary is noted on the inside front cover on p. [1].
    - "Poetry Copied by Gissing," [Lindow Grove School, Alderly Edge, Cheshire?], [1873?] (Box 7, Folder 154)
      Note on p. [1]: "I suppose about the year 1873. G.R.G. 1879." Contents include Gray's "Elegy" and Shelley's "To a Skylark." Laid in is: p. 379-80 of "Temple Bar," vol. 69, no. 276, Nov. 1883. Gissing's "Song" is on p. 379.
    - "Reminiscences of My Father, Jotted Down from Time to Time as They Chance to Occur to Me", 1884 (Box 7, Folder 155)
      Autograph manuscript.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Three photographs of George Gissing, 1884, 1895, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Seven photographs of places of interest in Gissing's life, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 157)
      1) Eversley, Worple Road, Epsom, England. 2) 62 Milton Street, London, N.W., England. 3) 7K Cornwall Residences, Regents Park, London. 4) George Gissing's birthplace. 5) Ciboure, Basses, Pyrenees, France, George Gissing's grave. 6) Plaque in the entrance to the Chemist's shop, birthplace of Gissing. 7) Lindow Grove School, Alderley Edge, Cheshire, England.
  - OTHER
    - Materials collected by Percival M. Stone about Gissing's residence in Waltham, Mass., 1941-53 (Box 7, Folder 158-160)
      Includes letters (two by Vincent Starrett), articles, clippings, photographs, and commencement program relating to Gissing's residence in Waltham, Mass., where he was a teacher of English in the Waltham High School in 1876-1877.
- Additions Since January 1997, [18]96 Apr 28; Series IV
  - ALS to Joseph Anderson, Eversley, Epson, [18]96 Apr 28 (Box 10, Folder 169)
    With: envelope and four clippings.
- Oversize, 1872-3
  - Honor, from Owens College, Manchester, for the Higher Junior (A) Greek class (in Series III), 1872-3 (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - Honor, from Owens College, Manchester, for the Higher Junior (A) Latin class (in Series III), 1872-3 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Honor, from Owens College, Manchester, for the Junior German class (in Series III), 1872-3 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Matriculation, from the University of London (in Series III), 1874 Jul 29 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Honor, from the University of London, certifying that Gissing was first in the list of candidates who obtained honors in English (in Series III), 1875 Oct 20 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Examination for the degree of Bachelor of Arts, from the University of London (in Series III), 1875 Oct 20 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Honor, from the University of London, certifying that Gissing was first in the list of candidates who obtained honors in Latin (in Series III), 1875 Oct 20 (Box 8, Folder 167)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 7, folder 159 (Box 9, Folder 168)